AKASH SARKAR

ANDROID DEVELOPER





+91 7838902089



akash.sarkar188@gmail.com



New Delhi



linkedin.com/in/akashsarkar188

SKILLS

- Java, Kotlin, Dart, Python
- Android App Development, Flutter
- Git, SQL, Postman
- Firebase, REST APIs
- Adobe XD, Figma

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY - CSE

Delhi Technical Campus

2016 - 2020

SENIOR SECONDARY - SCIENCE

Kendriya Vidyalaya Janakpuri

2015 - 2016

SECONDARY

Kendriya Vidyalaya Janakpuri

2013 - 2014

PROJECTS

ASPIRE BUDGETING

aspirebudgetmobile.app/

CORONA TRACKER

github.com/PsychoDevs69/CoronaTracker

PROFILE

A dedicated developer with a product mindset and a team player experienced in solving problems, making efficient and scalable apps, improving performance and driving product growth. Currently having 3.5 years of experience; Hunting for exceptional career opportunities!

EXPERIENCE

ANDROID DEVELOPER

SalaryBox (1M+ App downloads)

May 2021 - Nov 2023

Owned complete Android app and lead the development. Implemented Live tracking, payment gateway, geofencing, face detection, chat, card scanner, etc. Migrated modules to Kotlin, reduced app size and improved build time, performance, code structure and reduced crash rate. Researched and implemented successful growth hacks! Reduced app launch time for users on low-end devices.

ANDROID DEVELOPER

Canticle Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Sept 2020 - April 2021

Implemented face recognition, barcode scanner, offline attendance, attendance alarms, live tracking, etc. Revamped UX of existing app. Directly coordinated with clients to discuss real-life issues and solutions.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Achiredo Technologies LLP

Jan 2020 - Sept 2020

Improvised existing app by refactoring live location, bike booking, servicing and analytics screen. Developed new features and created UI designs for both android and web application.

ANDROID DEVELOPER

Ghar Pe Shiksha

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

Developed tutor and student app from scratch in Java, implemented chatbot, fragment architecture, dynamic forms, etc. Improved the code structure to make the apps scalable and structured.